[
  {
    "question": "The most important function of the nervous system is",
    "a": "regulation",
    "b": "motion",
    "c": "sensation",
    "d": "circulation",
    "e": "communication",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following fields is LEAST involved in the study of neuroscience?",
    "a": "geosciences",
    "b": "psychology",
    "c": "physics",
    "d": "computer science",
    "e": "mathematics",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most important nervous system cells for long-range communication are",
    "a": "astrocytes",
    "b": "microglia",
    "c": "Schwann cells",
    "d": "neurons",
    "e": "oligodendrocytes",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What distinguishes neurons from other cells in the body?",
    "a": "Neurons use RNA polymerase for transcription.",
    "b": "Neurons are much larger than most cells.",
    "c": "Neurons have no nucleus.",
    "d": "Neurons are only found in the brain.",
    "e": "Neurons are difficult to replace.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neurons mainly store genetic information in the form of",
    "a": "mRNA",
    "b": "polysaccharides",
    "c": "amino acids",
    "d": "tRNA",
    "e": "DNA",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following words is synonymous with 'cell body'?",
    "a": "cytosol",
    "b": "soma",
    "c": "dendrite",
    "d": "nucleus",
    "e": "axon",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following cell parts receives incoming information?",
    "a": "soma",
    "b": "dendrite",
    "c": "Node of Ranvier",
    "d": "antenna",
    "e": "axon",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word 'dendrite' is based on the Greek word for",
    "a": "'input'",
    "b": "'branching'",
    "c": "'spiny'",
    "d": "'afferent'",
    "e": "'treelike'",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main function of the axon is to",
    "a": "synthesize neurotransmitters",
    "b": "regulate gene expression",
    "c": "send outgoing information",
    "d": "store excess ions",
    "e": "receive incoming signals",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mammalian axon length can reach up to",
    "a": "one foot",
    "b": "one inch",
    "c": "several inches",
    "d": "several feet",
    "e": "half an inch",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What insulates axons?",
    "a": "microglia",
    "b": "phospholipids",
    "c": "myelin",
    "d": "neuronal membrane",
    "e": "Nodes of Ranvier",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of myelination is to",
    "a": "expedite signals that are sent down the axon",
    "b": "increase membrane permeability",
    "c": "restore neuronal membrane over time",
    "d": "make dendrites more receptive to incoming signals",
    "e": "inhibit unnecessary action potentials",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nodes of Ranvier are",
    "a": "sites of vesicle formation",
    "b": "points where dendrites intersect with the soma",
    "c": "points of neurotransmitter release",
    "d": "receptors of a post-synaptic neuron",
    "e": "gaps in the myelin sheath",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The axon meets the soma at the",
    "a": "somatic junction",
    "b": "axon hillock",
    "c": "synapse",
    "d": "Node of Ranvier",
    "e": "axon terminal",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the axon terminal,",
    "a": "the axon branches into multiple paths",
    "b": "action potentials are initiated",
    "c": "signals are received from the dendrite",
    "d": "signals are released as neurotransmitters",
    "e": "the postsynaptic neuron makes direct contact with the presynaptic neuron",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parts is NOT found in almost all neurons?",
    "a": "nucleus",
    "b": "soma",
    "c": "microglia",
    "d": "axon",
    "e": "dendrite",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neuron morphology is mainly a result of the neuron's",
    "a": "electrical potential",
    "b": "membrane strength",
    "c": "chemical composition",
    "d": "activity",
    "e": "function",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most textbook diagrams of neurons do NOT show",
    "a": "a single long axon",
    "b": "branching dendrites",
    "c": "a small cell body",
    "d": "the morphology of an interneuron",
    "e": "a central soma",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools is used to study the relationship between dendritic arbor structure and neuron function?",
    "a": "computer modeling",
    "b": "scanning electron microscopy (SEM)",
    "c": "transmission electron microscopy (TEM)",
    "d": "X-ray crystallography",
    "e": "magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Variations in neuron morphology BEST demonstrate the concept that",
    "a": "structure fits function",
    "b": "homeostasis is essential to life",
    "c": "cells respond to stimuli",
    "d": "size matters",
    "e": "life is highly ordered",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following sets of characteristics BEST describes a typical motor neuron?",
    "a": "soma at one end with many branching dendrites and a short axon",
    "b": "central soma with one large set of short dendrites and a long axon in the opposite direction",
    "c": "soma with a small set of dendrites and long axon",
    "d": "central soma with one dendrite and one axon",
    "e": "central soma with short dendrites and short axon",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following neuron types is most likely to have dendrites at both ends of the cell?",
    "a": "motor neuron",
    "b": "split-branch neuron",
    "c": "interneuron",
    "d": "sensory neuron",
    "e": "mirror neuron",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary task of sensory neurons is to",
    "a": "combine stimuli of all five senses into a complete picture",
    "b": "respond to stimuli",
    "c": "initiate emotions",
    "d": "interpret visual signals",
    "e": "transmit stimuli information to the brain",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main job of an interneuron is to",
    "a": "interpret information from the sensory neurons",
    "b": "serve as a link between other neurons",
    "c": "stimulate the formation of new neurons",
    "d": "translate electrical signals into chemical signals",
    "e": "develop into a specialized neuron",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Interneurons are best described as",
    "a": "small",
    "b": "curved",
    "c": "complex",
    "d": "round",
    "e": "long",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Grey matter includes",
    "a": "dendrites",
    "b": "myelin",
    "c": "cerebrospinal fluid",
    "d": "meninges tissue",
    "e": "the axon hillock",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "White matter does NOT contains",
    "a": "myelin",
    "b": "neurotransmitters",
    "c": "nuclei",
    "d": "Nodes of Ranvier",
    "e": "neuronal membranes",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes the distinct appearances of grey and white matter?",
    "a": "Light refraction causes grey matter to appear darker than white matter.",
    "b": "Grey and white matter appear to be distinct in MRI scans due to their molecular makeup.",
    "c": "Grey and white matter are only distinguishable on a microscopic level.",
    "d": "Axons of neurons with a common function will face the same direction.",
    "e": "Differences in blood vessel content cause grey and white matter to appear distinct.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Grey matter is most likely to be found",
    "a": "lining the ventricles",
    "b": "on the outside surfaces of the brain",
    "c": "exclusively in the brain stem",
    "d": "towards the center of the inside of the brain",
    "e": "around the hippocampus",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parts of the neuron is found just outside the spinal cord?",
    "a": "cell body",
    "b": "nuclear membrane",
    "c": "myelinated axons",
    "d": "dendrites",
    "e": "soma",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  }
]

